# Sakshi Kumari

**J** (+91) 9631211951

**≥** sakshisingh96312@gmail.com

in /in/sakshi-singh-692ba4276

# Objective

As a self-motivated B.tech graduate with specialization in AI and cloud computing, my goal is to apply my expertise and continue developing my skills to contribute to a dynamic team. With strong communication skills and a passion for learning, I am confident that I can excel in this field.

# Education

#### • Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science:

United University, Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh 2021-till date

#### • Higher Secondary Education:

Laxmi Narayan Dubey College, Motihari, Bihar 2019-2021

#### • High School:

Gyan Niketan Awasiye Vidyalaya, Motihari, Bihar High School 2018-2019

#### **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages: Java, Python, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Database Management: MySQL, node.js

Data Structures and Algorithm DevOps: Git, Docker, Jenkins

Artificial Intelligence: Machine Learning and Deep Learning

# Certifications

## • IBM certified Cloud Application Developer

- Issuing Authority: IBM

- Date Obtained: April 12, 2023

#### • IBM Certified Introduction To Python

- Issuing Authority: IBM

- Date Obtained: April 12, 2023

# • IBM Certified Introduction To HTML, CSS

- Issuing Authority: IBM

- Date Obtained: April, 2023

#### • IBM Certified Java Fundamentals

- Issuing Authority: IBM

- Date Obtained: April 14, 2023

#### • AI Certification

Issuing Authority: Expert SessionDate Obtained: June 15, 2024

# Experience

#### Intern, Adivid Technology, 1/06/2022 to 1/08/2022, Nashik

#### • RESTAURANT WEBSITE-The porch Cafe:-

- Developed frontend components using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to enhance user interface functionality.
- Implemented a user-friendly interface that includes menu displays, contact information, and interactive features for an engaging user experience.

#### • TRADING WEBSITE-Kota Factory:-

- Developed a dynamic trading website, inspired by the theme of "Kota Factory," using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Implemented features such as real-time stock updates, user authentication, and a streamlined trading interface.

### Prerogative Pointers(Student chapter), April 2024 - Present

#### • Social Media Head

– As Social Media Head, I developed and executed strategies to enhance engagement across platforms, created content that increased followers, collaborated on event promotions, and analyzed metrics to optimize campaign performance.

# Personal Projects

#### • AgroGinni - Agriculture based project

- -A major project choosen by us to grow interest in agriculture through interventions of technology.
- Develop well-tested models for application of agricultural research and technology for profitability of farming, and for income generation.
- This project include different modules like disese detection in plant, soil type testing, check deficiency of minerals for a particular crop and help farmers to overcome all the problems related to agriculture.
- Tools and technologies used: Python, ML, Vscode, raspberry pi, Jupyter Notebook, Postman.

#### • Vehicle Movement on a Map

- -Designed a web application that displays a vehicle moving on a map using leaflet library. The application should show the vehicle's current location and its path in real-time.
- -Show the vehicle's speed, distance etc. in real-time, updating every few seconds. Draw the route of the vehicle according to date and show the vehicle run on the route on the map.
- -Tools and technologies used: Leaflet, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, JSON.
- -Tools and technologies used: Python, OpenCV, Pycharm, Flask

#### • Hand Gesture Powerpoint Controller

- -This application is used by anyone to control their powerpoint presentation that recognise hand as a gesture and control powerpoint presentation.
- Implemented computer vision algorithms to capture, process, and analyze hand gestures through a webcam using OpenCV library in Python.
- Tools and technologies used: Python, OpenCV, Pycharm, Flask

#### • Criminal face detection

- -This applications use advanced facial recognition technology to identify individuals from images comparing theknown criminals and is used for security purpose.
- Tools and technologies used: Python, Pycharm, os, opency, face-recognition.

### Area Of Interest

Research based projects

Artificial Intelligence And Machine Learning

Software development and Programming

#### Quality

Leadership

**Problem Solving** 

Time management

#### AWARDS

• Awarded for Outstanding Hand Gesture Recognition Project.	2023
• Certificate of Appreciation for Coordinated Poster Presentation	2023
• Certificate of participation in hackathon	2024
• Awarded as a Social media head at Prerogative Pointers (Student Chap	oter) 2024